Guide to the Department of the History of Science and Medicine, School of Medicine, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of the History of Science and Medicine, School of Medicine, Yale University, records
1965-1979
RU 738
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
20.25
(50 boxes)
The records consist of administrative files, reports, correspondence, and personnel and student records documenting the Department of the History of Science and Medicine (known as the Department of the History of Medicine prior to 1959) at the Yale Medical School. Included are the records of the department chairs John Farquhar Fulton, Frederick Lawrence Holmes, Derek John de Solla Price, and Lloyd Grenfell Stevenson, and the correspondence of professors George Rosen and Henry Ernest Sigerist.
Yale University. School of Medicine
Fulton, John F. (John Farquhar), 1899-1960
Holmes, Frederic Lawrence, 1932-2003
Price, Derek J. de Solla (Derek John de Solla), 1922-1983
Stevenson, Lloyd G., 1918-
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-E (YRG 27-E), Records of departments, offices, programs, and projects of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of administrative files, reports, correspondence, and personnel and student records documenting the Department of the History of Science and Medicine (known as the Department of the History of Medicine prior to 1959) at the Yale Medical School. Included are the records of the department chairs John Farquhar Fulton, Frederick Lawrence Holmes, Derek John de Solla Price, and Lloyd Grenfell Stevenson, and the correspondence of professors George Rosen and Henry Ernest Sigerist.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in eight series: I. Background Records and Annual Reports. II. Correspondence. III. Records of Journals, Books and Articles. IV. Administrative Records. V. Projects and Exhibits. VI. Colloquia, Course Information and General Student Matters. VI. Grants. VII. Personnel and Student Records.
Medicine -- History -- Study and teaching; Science -- History -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Rosen, George, 1910-1977; Sigerist, Henry E. (Henry Ernest), 1891-1957; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Employees; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Department of the History of Medicine; Yale University. Department of the History of Science and Medicine; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records, Accession 1986-A-091
  - Background Records and Annual Reports, 1957-1977
    Conditions Governing Access
    The materials are open for research.
    - Organization of the Department, 1959-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - Publicity and congratulations letters on formation of new department, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Department of History of Science and Medicine, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Governing Board, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Meeting of the Governing Board and staff, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual report re: proposed organization, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual reports
      - 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
      - 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Ten Year Report (1951-1961) (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - 1959-1970 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Requests for annual reports, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence, 1951-1982; Series II
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2018.
    - Correspondence files of Chairmen John Farguhar Fulton, Derek John de Solla Price and Lloyd Grenfell Stevenson
      - A, 1957-1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Academy of Medicine, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - American Association for the History of Medicine, 1963-1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Association of American Medical Colleges, 1965-1970 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - B, 1952-1972 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
      - Brewster, Kingman, 1959-1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Butler Hospital, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - C, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
      - Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - D, 1958-1972 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - To: Dean of Graduate School (de Solla Price), 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Department-Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1960-1968 (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - Dictionary of Scientific Biography, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - Dissenters, 1964-1968 (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - E, 1957-1969 (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - F, 1958-1970 (Box 6, Folder 41)
      - John F. Fulton Memorial Award Committee, 1964-1972 (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Fulton Society, 1962-1969 (Box 7, Folder 49)
      - G, 1958-1972 (Box 7, Folder 50-51)
      - Graham, Donald C. (Canadian Medical Association Journal), 1965 (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - H, 1958-1968 (Box 8, Folder 58-59)
      - Hafner Medical Prize, 1964-1971 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - History of Medicine-new departments at other universities, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - History of Science Society, Chairman, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Yale: Office of the Secretary-Holden, 1960-1963 (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - I, 1954-1966 (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - J, 1957-1971 (Box 8, Folder 67)
      - K, 1958-1976 (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - L, 1952-1970 (Box 9, Folder 74)
      - M, 1956-1971 (Box 9, Folder 79)
      - M, 1956-1971 (Box 10, Folder 80)
      - Mc, 1955-1969 (Box 10, Folder 81)
      - N, 1951-1961 (Box 10, Folder 86)
      - O, 1964-1972 (Box 10, Folder 88)
      - P-Q, 1958-1971 (Box 10, Folder 89)
      - Office of the Provost, 1963-1965 (Box 11, Folder 95)
      - R, 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 97)
      - R, 1958-1971 (Box 11, Folder 98)
      - S, 1952-1962 (Box 12, Folder 108)
      - S, 1962-1971 (Box 12, Folder 109-110)
      - Sweat (English) Stanley Wing Handford, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - T, 1952-1962 (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - T, 1961-1968 (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - U, 1952-1958 (Box 13, Folder 119)
      - U, 1964-1966 (Box 13, Folder 120)
      - V, 1953-1962 (Box 13, Folder 121)
      - V, 1964-1970 (Box 13, Folder 122)
      - W, 1953-1962 (Box 13, Folder 123)
      - W, 1963-1970 (Box 13, Folder 124-125)
      - X-Y-Z, 1964-1967 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - Correspondence files of Frederick Lawrence Holmes
      - A, 1965-1978 (Box 14, Folder 129)
      - B, 1967-1976 (Box 14, Folder 130-131)
      - B, 1965-1976 (Box 14, Folder 132)
      - B, 1977-1978 (Box 14, Folder 133)
      - C, 1965-1978 (Box 14, Folder 134)
      - Canada Council Grant, 1972-1977 (Box 14, Folder 135)
      - Canadian Society for The Study of the History and Philosophy of Science, 1972-1976 (Box 14, Folder 137)
      - Canadian Society for The Study of the History and Philosophy of Science, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 138)
      - D, 1971-1978 (Box 15, Folder 142)
      - Dictionary of Scientific Biography (Charles Gillespie, ed.), 1964-1981 (Box 15, Folder 143)
      - E, 1975-1978 (Box 15, Folder 144)
      - F, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 146)
      - F, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 147)
      - Faculty of Arts, 1975-1976 (Box 15, Folder 148)
      - Faculty Association, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 149)
      - G, 1975-1978 (Box 15, Folder 156)
      - H, 1975-1981 (Box 16, Folder 165)
      - H, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 166)
      - Harvard University Press, 1969-1977 (Box 16, Folder 170)
      - History Department-University of Western Ontario, 1972-1976 (Box 16, Folder 171)
      - History of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology-Committee on
        - 1975-1976 (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 172)
        - 1975-1976 (2 of 2) (Box 17, Folder 173)
        - 1977 (Box 17, Folder 174)
      - I, 1976 September (Box 17, Folder 180)
      - I, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 181)
      - Institute for History and Philosophy of Science an Technology (University of Toronto), 1973-1975 (Box 17, Folder 183)
      - International Congress of History of Medicine, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 184)
      - J, 1973-1976 (Box 17, Folder 185)
      - K, 1973-1978 (Box 17, Folder 187)
      - L, 1973-1976 (Box 17, Folder 192)
      - L, 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 193)
      - M, 1963-1976 (Box 17, Folder 197)
      - M, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 198)
      - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1964-1976 (Box 18, Folder 205)
      - N, 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 209)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities., 1973-1975 (Box 18, Folder 211)
      - National Institutes of Health Training Grants, 1968-1972 (Box 18, Folder 212)
      - National Library of Medicine-Bethesda, MD, 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 213)
      - National Science Foundation, 1974-1977 (Box 18, Folder 214)
      - O, 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 215)
      - P, 1974-1978 (Box 18, Folder 217)
      - Q, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 222)
      - R, 1972-1978 (Box 18, Folder 223)
      - Reprint Requests, 1963-1978 (Box 18, Folder 225)
      - S, 1972-1981 (Box 19, Folder 228)
      - S, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 229)
      - T, 1973-1976 (Box 19, Folder 235)
      - U, 1972-1977 (Box 19, Folder 241)
      - V, 1973 March (Box 19, Folder 242)
      - W, 1973-1978 (Box 19, Folder 244)
      - Watson, Neale (Publishing Company), 1972-1975 (Box 19, Folder 245)
      - Wellcome Unit-Cambridge, England, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 246)
      - Y, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 252)
      - Z, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 253)
  - Records of Journals, books and articles, 1956-1979; Series III
    - Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences, 1960-1970
      - Correspondence and receipts
        - A, 1960-1966 (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - B, 1960-1963 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - C, 1960-1963 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - D, 1960-1963 (Box 20, Folder 4)
        - E, 1960-1963 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - F, 1960-1964 (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - G, 1960-1963 (Box 20, Folder 7)
        - G, 1963-1966 (Box 21, Folder 8)
        - H, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 9)
        - H, 1963-1968 (Box 21, Folder 10)
        - I-K, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 12)
        - I-K, 1963-1969 (Box 21, Folder 13)
        - L, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 15)
        - L, 1963-1968 (Box 22, Folder 16)
        - M, 1960-1963 (Box 22, Folder 18-19)
        - M, 1963-1969 (Box 22, Folder 20)
        - J.A. Majors, 1963-1969 (Box 22, Folder 21)
        - N-O, 1960-1963 (Box 23, Folder 23)
        - N-O, 1963-1966 (Box 23, Folder 24)
        - P-Q, 1960-1963 (Box 23, Folder 25)
        - P-Q, 1963-1969 (Box 23, Folder 26)
        - Pitman, 1961-1964 (Box 23, Folder 27)
        - R, 1960-1963 (Box 23, Folder 28)
        - R, 1960-1963 (Box 23, Folder 29)
        - S, 1963-1969 (Box 24, Folder 30)
        - S, 1963-1969 (Box 24, Folder 31)
        - Stechert-Hafner, 1960-1969 (Box 24, Folder 32)
        - T-V, 1963-1968 (Box 24, Folder 34)
        - T-V, 1963-1969 (Box 24, Folder 35)
        - Turner, 1960-1963 (Box 24, Folder 36)
        - W-Z, 1963-1968 (Box 24, Folder 37)
        - W-Z, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Medical Monograph Series, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - George Rosen Articles
      - American Journal of Public Health-Petty accounts, 1971-1974 (Box 26, Folder 54)
      - "The American Journal of Public Health: Antecedents, Origin and Evolution..", 1972 (Box 26, Folder 55)
      - "The First Neighborhood Health Center Movement; Its Rise and Fall" (EPH 110a), 1974 (Box 26, Folder 56)
      - "Historical Trends and Future Prospects In Public Health" (EPH 110a), 1974 (Box 27, Folder 57)
      - "Medical Care-Health Needs and Resources in the U.S." (EPH 110a), 1974 (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - "The Impact of the Hospital on the Physician, the Patient and the Community" (EPH 110a), 1974 (Box 27, Folder 59)
      - "Nicholas Senn's Experimental Work on Cancer Transmissibility", 1977 (Box 27, Folder 60)
      - Requests for copies of articles, 1975-1979 (Box 27, Folder 61)
      - Bibliography, undated (Box 27, Folder 62)
      - Vitae and Obituaries, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 63)
      - Miscellaneous Yale Business, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 64)
      - Conference on Preventive Medicine, correspondence: Thomas Dublin, 1974-1975 (Box 27, Folder 65)
      - Conference: SUNY Binghamton, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 66)
      - Conference: McMaster University Ontario, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 67)
      - Correspondence
        - re: posthumous re-publication of articles, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 72)
        - A-H, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 73)
        - I-Q, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 74)
        - R-Z, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 75)
  - Administrative records, 1951-1978; Series IV
    - AAHM meeting, New Haven, 1967 April (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Admissions, 1962-1968 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Air conditioning, 1951-1954 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Alumni Association (Yale), 1964-1965 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - American Bibliographical Center, 1970 December (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - American Institute of the History of Pharmacy, 1965-1970 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1961-1970 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Board of Permanent Officers, 1964-1966 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Bookbindery, 1963, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Columbia, 1966-1968 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Committee to Reevaluate the Goals of Medical Education, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Computer Center, 1964-1965 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Computer Center, 1969-1971 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Departments of History of Science and Medicine in other centers, 1962-1969 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Directives, 1967-1970 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Courses/Theses/Exams, 1963-1970 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Faculty, 1961-1970 (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - General Administrative Procedure, 1953, 1962-1969 (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - Grants and Awards, 1965-1969 (Box 30, Folder 19)
      - Student, 1962-1970 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Fellowships, 1954-1965 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Films, 1952-1954 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Films in Medical History, 1966-1969 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Finances and Budget (Department of the History of Medicine), 1952-1966 (Box 30, Folder 24-25)
    - Graduate School, 1963-1965 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Graduate Students-General, 1960-1964 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Historiography, 1964 March (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Institute of Early American History and Culture, 1964-1970 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - International Academy of the History of Medicine, 1964, 1970-1976 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - International Academy of the History of Science and Medicine (G. Rosen, Director)-International Congress, Yale, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 31-32)
    - International Academy of the History of Science and Medicine (G. Rosen, Director)-Macy Foundation Grant, 1976 (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Jobs for graduates, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Leaves of absence, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Maps, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Medical Center long range building plans, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Medical School Council, 1969-1977 (Box 31, Folder 38-40)
    - Meetings, departmental, 1964-1966 (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Miami, University of-Advisory Committee, 1964 November (Box 32, Folder 42)
    - Minutes-departmental, 1961-1968 (Box 32, Folder 43)
    - National Science Foundation, 1954-1966 (Box 32, Folder 44)
    - National Society for Medical Research, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 45)
    - Pierson College, 1963-1966 (Box 32, Folder 46)
    - Postdoctoral Health Insurance, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 47)
    - Recommendations, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 48)
    - Reprinting Services, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 49)
    - Reprints-Lloyd G. Stevenson, 1964-1969 (Box 32, Folder 50)
    - Safety hints, 1973-1976 (Box 32, Folder 51)
    - Secretary, office of the, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 52)
    - Social Sciences Club, 1964-1967 (Box 32, Folder 53)
    - Speaking Engagements-1964, 1963-1964 (Box 32, Folder 54)
    - Speaking Engagements-1965, 1964-1965 (Box 32, Folder 55)
    - Speaking Engagements, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 56)
    - Standing orders-department publications, 1961-1972 (Box 32, Folder 57)
    - Summer Fellowships, 1967-1971 (Box 32, Folder 58)
    - Surveys, 1966-1971 (Box 32, Folder 59)
    - University Bulletins, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 61)
    - Vitas submitted, 1960-1961 (Box 33, Folder 62)
    - Welch Medal Committee, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 63)
    - Women in Medicine, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 64)
    - Woodrow Wilson Fellows, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 65)
    - Yale College, 1963-1967 (Box 33, Folder 66)
    - Yale Health plan, 1971-1973 (Box 33, Folder 67)
    - Yale Medical Library, 1963-1967 (Box 33, Folder 68-69)
    - Yale University Press, 1964 (Box 33, Folder 70)
    - Yale University-programs in International and Area Studies, 1963-1964 (Box 33, Folder 71)
    - Yale Weekly Bulletin and Calendar, 1971-1978 (Box 33, Folder 72)
  - Photographs, 1863-1921, 1966-1981; Series V
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2017.
    - Exhibits
      - "Medical Poets", 1971 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - "The Sounds of the Chest", 1971 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - "Dreams", 1972 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - "Tuberculosis-some highlights", 1972 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - "Pellenkofer and Virchow", 1973 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - "Chest Surgery", 1973-1974 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - "Injections", 1974 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - "Medicine in the Enlightened Eighteenth Century", 1975 (Box 34, Folder 8)
      - "Albert Schweitzer", 1975 (Box 34, Folder 9)
      - "Child Abuse and Neglect", 1976 (Box 34, Folder 10)
      - Student exhibit, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 11)
      - "Goiter and Cretinism", 1976 (Box 35, Folder 12)
      - "Medicine in Pre-Revolutionary Era", 1976 (Box 35, Folder 13)
      - "The Diaphragm in Health and Disease", 1976-1977 (Box 35, Folder 14)
      - "Medical History at Yale: the First 25 Years", 1978 (Box 35, Folder 15)
      - "The Body-Mind Problem in History", 1980-1981 (Box 35, Folder 16)
      - "Edwin Klebs", undated (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - "Astrology and Medicine", undated (Box 35, Folder 18)
      - "Mercury in History", undated (Box 35, Folder 19)
      - "Psychosomatic Illness", undated (Box 35, Folder 20)
      - "Pellagra", undated (Box 35, Folder 21)
      - "The Doctor and the Automobile", undated (Box 35, Folder 22)
      - "What is Orthopaedic Surgery?", undated (Box 35, Folder 23)
      - "Public Health is a Community Affair", undated (Box 35, Folder 24)
    - Temkin Festschrift Project-correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 25-26)
    - Temkin Festschrift Project-papers, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 27-28)
    - Workshops
      - "The Methodology of the History of Psychiatry", 1966 April (Box 36, Folder 29-30)
        - Budget, 1966 April (Box 37, Folder 31)
        - Correspondence, 1966 April (Box 37, Folder 32)
        - Expenses, 1966 April (Box 37, Folder 33)
      - Schering "History of Medicine in Canada" Round-table discussion, 1966 September (Box 37, Folder 34)
      - Translation of Bloch's "Les rois Thaumaturgeo"-correspondence, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Colloquia, course information and general student matters, 1949-1978; Series VI
    - Colloquia
      - 1960-1963 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - 1963-1964 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - 1960-1973 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Courses-department, etc., 1949-1966 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Courses-department, 1966-1969 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Course Catalog (Director of Undergraduate Studies), 1968-1976 (Box 38, Folder 6-7)
    - Clinical Entities 105, 1955-1956 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Harvey (Samuel C.) Lectures, undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - History of Medicine 110: Public Health, 1951-1956 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - History of Medicine Seminars, 1957-1963 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - History of Psychiatry 109a (seminar), 1960-1961 (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - History of Science and Medicine
      - Miscellaneous, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - 402a, 1964-1967 (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - 28a-exams, Fall 1975 (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - 28a -midterm (grades), Fall 1975 (Box 39, Folder 16)
      - 28a-student matters, Fall 1975 (Box 39, Folder 17)
      - 29b-Health In the City-reading lists, Spring 1976 (Box 39, Folder 18)
      - Health In the City-student lists, Spring 1976 (Box 39, Folder 19)
      - 28a-exams, Fall 1976 (Box 39, Folder 20)
      - 28a-Humor chart, Fall 1976 (Box 39, Folder 22)
      - 28a-maps, Fall 1976 (Box 39, Folder 23)
      - 28a-reading lists, Fall 1976 (Box 39, Folder 24)
      - Student lists, Fall 1976 (Box 39, Folder 25)
      - 39b-The Structure of Medical Practice, Spring 1977 (Box 39, Folder 26)
      - 39b/80b-student lists, Spring 1977 (Box 39, Folder 27)
      - 321a/721a, Fall 1977 (Box 39, Folder 28)
      - 101 (Anatomy 109), 1949-1966 (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - History of Surgery 102, 1954-1965 (Box 39, Folder 30-31)
    - Public Health 110-Core readings, undated (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - Medical School course-Topics in the History of Medicine, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - College Seminars A/C, 1970-1972 (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - Copy for catalog, 1951-1970 (Box 39, Folder 35-36)
    - Graduate Trainee enquiries, 1960-1968 (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - Graduate Trainee enquiries, 1960-1968 (Box 40, Folder 38)
    - Student lists/photos/class assignments, 1968-1971 (Box 40, Folder 39)
    - Undergraduate enrollments, 1978 (Box 40, Folder 40)
    - Undergraduate major, 1961-1966 (Box 40, Folder 41-42)
    - Yale College students, 1975-1976 (Box 40, Folder 43)
  - Grants, 1959-1975; Series VII
    - NIH Grant-application-Fulton, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - NIH Grant-application for second NIH Grant refused, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - NSF Grants
      - ENSFGN 299-Price, 1964-1966 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - GN 527-Price, 1966-1968 (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - EGN 527-Price-expenses, 1966-1968 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - GN-527-Price, 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 13)
      - GN-527-Price Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 42, Folder 14)
      - General, 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Grad. Stud. Res.-Hist. Sci. Med. (9060-41-1976840), 1969-1971 (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - NSF Grant: changes 0000l by month, 1971-1972 (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Grant: Dr. Paul's expenses, 1970-1972 (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - NSF Graduate Traineeships, 1966-1967 (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Training Grant application, 1969 (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - PHS Training Grant application (G. Rosen), 1972 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Personnel and student records, 1951-1978; Series VIII
    Restricted until Jan 1, 2054.
    - Faculty Personnel
    - Non-Faculty Personnel
      - Bursary students, 1951-1978 (Box 47, Folder 27)
      - General, 1951-1969 (Box 47, Folder 28)
      - Temporary Non-Faculty, 1958-1970 (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Student Records